ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草告别狂人们
磁芯升级成机械章鱼X
翻译
电脑团
小酸奶!
翻译
吃冰棒
TL
翻译
时间轴
大葱ALX  念念  今
电脑狂人
第四季
第十集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
丹妮丝占卜别说话
她都知道
交响乐投资
想你和海
爱你的  琼
不死鸟
乔·麦克米伦  人文科学
每个人都需要朋友  就算是一棵老树
Everybody needs a friend, even an old tree.
用描线笔
Okay, now, take our liner brush.
轻描
Paint thinner.
轻轻抹上去
Want to thin it down.
非常非常轻地涂上一层棕色
Thin some brown down, very, very thin. Very thin.
多用稀释剂
A lot of paint thinner.
我们画上一两根枝丫
Let's put a little arm or two.
也许这棵老树根本没有叶子
Maybe this old tree don't have any leaves.
也许它已经...到了落叶时节
Maybe he's already retired for the -- for the year.
喂
Hello?
是我
It's me.
怎么了  没事吧
What's going on? I-Is everything okay?
我能告诉你一些事吗
Can I just tell you something?
好啊  当然可以了
Uh, yeah, o-of course you can.
招待所里有个德国人
Okay, so there's this German guy in the hostel
名叫奥托
named Otto.
是吗  长得帅吗
Oh, yeah? Is he cute?
反正...
Anyway...
他跟我说有个古庙遗迹
he was telling me about this ancient temple ruin.
其实  他一直说个不停
Actually, he was going on and on about it
凌晨三点半我都想睡觉了他还在说
3:30 in the morning while I was trying to sleep
我想拿我的《孤独星球》
and I wanted to bash his head in
拍他的脑袋
with my "Lonely Planet" guide.
但听起来感觉很棒
But it sounded kind of awesome.
那个...神庙遗迹吗
This, uh -- the temple ruin?
是的  那里100多年前被入侵者烧毁了
Yeah, it was burned to the ground by raiders like 100 years ago.
我问奥托我能不能一起去
I asked Otto if I could go with him,
他说可以
and he said yes.
那地方空旷无人
This place was wild, empty.
是一个神圣之城
It was a major shrine city.
我们的导游阿特
Okay, anyway, Aat, our guide,
带我们到一棵树前  那棵树...
he brought us to this tree, and it had this --
里面有一颗砂岩佛祖头
this sandstone head of the Buddha in it.
树根包裹着这颗头
And the roots of the tree had completely grown around it
只露出了它的脸
and covered everything except its face.
然后...
And...
阿特让我们靠近后
Aat had us get on our -- our hands and our knees
得跪在地上
as we got closer to it
因为你不能俯视佛祖
because you can't look down at the Buddha.
必须要尊敬佛祖
You have to be respectful,
所以我们爬了过去
so we crawled up to it,
我伸手去碰了一下那些树根
and, um, I reached out and I-I touched the roots,
阿特将头磕在地上
and Aat put his forehead to the ground...
我们也照做了
so we did, too.
我们不是在拜佛祖
And it's not like we were worshipping the Buddha
或者什么雕像
or the statue, you know?
更像是...
It was, like...
拜这棵树...
more of the tree...
为它屹立至今...
for what it was doing, and...
还有烧毁的石头和草地
burned stones and grass.
反正  然后开始下雨
Anyway, it, um, started to rain.
我把我的前额磕在泥土上时
And when I put my forehead to the mud,
我想到了爸爸
I thought about Dad...
他好像仍然在我身边
...like he was still with me,
只是以另一种方式
Just in, like, a different way.
亲爱的  你说的太美了
Honey, that's beautiful.
挺棒的
It's pretty cool.
我觉得也许你和我  我们其实挺像的
I think maybe you and I, we're actually pretty similar,
所以我们才经常吵架
and maybe that's why we fight all the time,
你知道吗
you know?
是啊  是啊
Yeah, yeah.
我知道
I do.
该死  我的电话卡没钱了
Oh, shit, my calling card is running out.
爱你  妈妈  再见
I love you, Mom! Bye!
好了
There.
这样  这幅画应该就画好了
Shoot, I think with that, we about have a finished painting.
祝你好运
Good luck.
-祝你好运  麦奇  -谢谢  乔
- Good luck, Mikey. - Thanks, Joe.
谢谢  乔
Thanks, Joe.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不  说真的
No, really.
彗星是...一个奇迹
Comet was...a miracle.
真希望我们能坚持久一点
Wish we could've done it longer.
你做的决定没错
You made the right call.
正如你所说
Like you said,
坐在这里看着世界毁灭我们
it would've been a bummer to sit around here
是一件很痛苦的事
and watch the world swallow us up.
谢谢
Thanks.
我喜欢这里
I like this place.
我知道现在没这种感觉
I know it doesn't feel like it now,
但是这是一个开始
but this is the start of something.
-但现在  -没错  现在
- But now... - Yeah! Now!
天啊  我得加快步伐
Oh, my goodness. I have get ready fast.
不好意思  你现在营业吗
I'm sorry, are you -- Are you open?
等等
Wait.
奥西里斯
Osiris!
声音小一点  亲爱的
Turn down the tube, babe.
坐吧
Well, sit down.
请坐
Please, have a seat.
读掌纹20
Okay, so it's gonna be, uh, $20 for a palm reading
掌纹加塔罗牌30
and $30 for palm and cards.
谢谢
Thank you.
能让我看看你的手吗
May I see your palm, please?
对不起
Yikes, I'm sorry.
但你的莎莎酱线看上去很不错
buyour salsa line looks pretty good, huh?
对不起
Sorry.
生命线很长
Long life line.
在这里和这里有断点
broken here and there.
很多挑战
Lot of challenges.
改变
Changes.
挑战和改变
Challenges and changes, huh?
真意外啊
Shocking.
那是什么
What's that?
对固执的考验
Test for stubbornness.
智慧线很明显
Sharp head line.
很聪明
Smart.
成功
Successful.
可能...有点自私
Little...selfish maybe?
情感线看上去...
Heart line seems to say...
有爱
some love.
有失
Some loss.
丹妮丝  别打擦边球了
Come on, Denise, enough softballs.
你今天为什么来找我
Why'd you come in here today?
命运
Destiny.
能吃甜点吗
Dessert now?
甜点  你刚狼吞虎咽吃完了那些玉米片
Dessert? You just scarfed down those nachos!
-要几个  -两个
- How many? - Two.
就两个
Just two?
好的  好好玩
Okay. Have fun.
那是我的孙子  奥西里斯
That -- That's my grandson, Osiris.
谢谢你
Thanks for your time.
等等  你不做塔罗牌占卜了吗
Wait, don't you want your card reading?
你都付钱了
You paid for it.
请把你的右手放在牌上
Would you please put your right hand on the deck?
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
过去
Past.
现在
Present.
未来
Future.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
其实这些牌
Well, you know, they really mean
你想让它们有什么意思就是什么意思
whatever you want them to mean.
就是
Well, you know,...
毁灭
destruction.
-毁灭  -是的
- Destruction? - Yeah.
一般来说
Commonly.
悲恸  彷徨  痛苦
Agony, indecision, misery.
天啊
Christ.
所以我又失败了
So I lose again?
好吧
Okay, great.
不  不一定
No. Not necessarily.
因为你看这些阴云
Because, you see, this golden horizon
后面的金色地平线
behind the storm clouds,
可能有点意义
that could be something.
-这张能给我吗  -当然了
- Can I keep this? - Sure.
20元一包牌
I sell packs for another $20.
天啊  你没事吧
Jesus! You okay?
乔·麦克米伦
Joe MacMillan?
就这样  我们在个人电脑行业中完蛋了
And like that, we're getting killed in the PC business.
-谁猜得到呢  -我
- Who'd have guessed, right? - Me.
当然了
Of course.
除了你
Besides you.
乔  我想说
Can I just say, Joe,
看你这么多年一路奋斗走来真的很刺激
it's been a kick watching you carve a path all these years.
一直走在最前面
Always on the bleeding edge.
远超一切
I mean, way out there.
我们不少人
More than a few of us
真的开始相信你的指引了
really grew to trust your finger in the air.
叶子变色了吗
Have the leaves changed yet?
-什么  -东岸那边
- What? - Back east.
嗯  刚开始
Yeah. Just started.
非常美丽
It's gorgeous.
好了  我得去机场了
All right, better get to SFO.
现在都让我们飞商务舱了
They got us flying business class now.
能相信吗
Believe it?
别  我来付
No, please, I got it.
等不及看你接下来的计划了  乔
Can't wait to see what you do next, Joe.
唐娜在快速拨号列表上
Donna is on speed dial.
我们就把你们安排在这里了
I think we're gonna have you guys set up here.
太好了
Okay, great.
太感谢你能接纳我们了
Thank you so much for having us.
-能来这儿我好兴奋  -不用谢我
- I'm so excited to be here. - Don't thank me.
太好了
Yes.
好了  东西在这儿
Okay, so we've got this here.
这看起来太普通了
That's so common.
这边上有按钮
There's, like, buttons on the side.
不不不  约翰
No, no, no, John.
-不  我要  -不  听我的  你得...
- No, I'm gonna -- - No, I'm telling you, you got to --
-我正在这么做  -那是约翰
- I'm trying to do that. - Uh, that was John.
-让我来  -不  我要...
- Let me try. - No, no, I want to --
-让我试试  -至少让我试试吧
- Let me just try it. - Let me at least try.
看着  看着
Look, look, look.
你们要去哪  我买了墨西哥卷
Where you guys going? We got tacos.
卷饼时间  大家伙
Taco time, you guys!
快过来拿
Come and get 'em.
很好
Good.
这是什么  我看到的是什么
What is this? What are we looking at?
这是一个基因片段的十分之一  但...
So, this is one tenth of 1% of one little gene, but this...
你没事吧
Are you all right?
没事
Oh, yeah.
你在飞机上给我的醒鼻凝胶
That nasal gel you gave me on the plane,
感觉就像是一只鼻涕虫爬进了我的鼻子
it feels like a slug crawled into my nose
然后拉了坨屎
and took a dump.
等你没生病时  就会感谢我了
Well, you'll thank me when you don't get sick.
我怎么能为没发生的事感谢你
How will I thank you for something that doesn't happen?
能听到你为什么事感谢什么人会很好的
It would be neat to hear you thank somebody for something.
和顶级投资人在国外待了两个月
Two months abroad with top investors,
我们却还没有什么拿得出手的
and we've got nothing to show for it.
到了奥斯陆以北
Yeah, well, it's tough for the work to translate
就比较难翻译了
once we got north of Oslo.
目的其实在于让你
Well, the point was to get you in good
-认识一些真正的欧洲竞争者  -竞争者
- with some real European players. - Players?
天哪  我都说不出那些人除了
My God, I couldn't tell you what any of those people did
去高档餐厅吃晚饭和抬身价还做了什么
save for go out to dinner at fancy restaurants and name drop.
这一趟到底花了多少钱
How much did this trip even cost?
反正花的是我的钱
Well, it's my money,
我花这钱是为了让你实现你的想法
and I'm spending it to help you bring your ideas to fruition.
-好吧  -但如果你只打算坐在这里
- Okay. - But if you're just gonna sit there
像个只会讽刺人的混蛋一样贬低别人
and cut everyone down like some sardonic asshole --
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我表现得对你来说不够好
I didn't perform well enough for you.
我不是你的玩偶
I'm not your monkey.
我知道你还在处理一些私人问题
Look, I know that you're still dealing with some personal issues.
或者...可能...
Or...maybe...
你只是失去了兴趣
you're just losing interest
因为现在你需要
because now's the part of the process
真正去做些工作
you actually have to do some work
而不是仅仅吹嘘各种可能性了
and not just bullshit about the possibilities.
能停在这儿吗
Can you pull over here?
卡梅伦
Cameron.
Cameron!
那你是怎么回家的
How did you even get home?
我走了两公里到了一家麦当劳
Just walked a mile to the McDonald's,
借他们的电话打了个车  花了200美金
used their phone to call a cab, cab cost $200.
你应该打给我的
You should've called me at home.
我可喜欢麦当劳了  他们的小苹果派
I love me some McDonald's -- them little apple pies.
非常美味
Delis-cous.
那之后你们再谈过吗
So, have you talked since?
-两周了  什么动静都没有  -不是吧
- Two weeks. Just radio silence. - Oh, no.
-我觉得是没戏了  -好吧
- So I think that's done. - Yeah.
我记得计算机科学里
You know, there's this thing
有个东西叫
in CompSci I remember --
递归
recursion.
就是一个程序里
Where a specific function
一个函数不断调用自己
calls upon itself repeatedly within a program.
为了解决整个问题
So in order to solve the big problem,
它不断利用小问题作为答案
it uses the same small problem over and over
从而使问题越来越复杂
as the solution to increasingly complex issues.
而这  朋友  就是我软件的原理
And that, my friend, is how my software runs.
顺便说下  乔的事我很遗憾
Sorry about Joe, by the way.
谢谢
Thanks.
其实我还有一些
I actually still have
他的东西需要还
some stuff of his to give back,
但我就是想都不能想
but I just can't bear the thought
现在去见他  你明白吗
of seeing him right now, you know?
我能说句话吗
Can I tell you something?
你说
Yeah?
你心里充满了爱
You got a lot of love in you.
比我认识的任何人都要多
More than anybody I ever met.
它从你心里喷涌而出
It's bursting out of you.
你大口大口地接受这个世界
You're taking the world in these -- in these big gulps,
没法不让自己溺死在里面
and you can't help but to let yourself get drowned in it.
让你迷茫  让你活得好像
Overwhelms you, makes you live like
随时都要爆炸
you're ready to explode at any minute.
他们看不到这点
They don't see it.
而我看到了
I do.
你承受着这样的负担
It's a burden you carry.
你不认为我只是再次逃开吗
You don't think I'm just running away again?
你可能是吧
Oh, I -- you might be.
我在想佛罗里达
I'm thinking about Florida.
佛罗里达  佛罗里达有什么
Florida? What the hell's in Florida?
那里除了鳄鱼和该死的艾波卡特公园还有什么
They got alligators and that dadgum Epcot Center? What?
我妈
My mom.
老天  我只是不想再告别了  你懂吗
Man, I'm just tired of saying goodbye, you know?
递归
Recursion.
没错
Exactly.
也许你该让自己犯一次心脏病
Maybe you ought to have yourself a heart attack.
-是吗  -是  对啊
- Yeah? - Yeah, yeah.
当然
Sure.
你知道吗  我倒下时
You know, when I went down,
我尽我所能继续留下
I did everything I could to stay in the ring.
疯狂抵抗
Fought like hell.
我的脑子里在不停念叨
Had this mantra in my head.
撑住  撑住  撑住
"Just stay in it, stay in it, stay in it."
但我当时快输了
But I was losing.
当时我就知道如果我不放弃
I knew at that moment if I didn't give up,
会被杀死的
that guy's gonna kill me.
我
I...
我没有什么可放弃的了
I got nothing left to give up.
我知道  如果你留下来  这很难
I know it's -- If you stay, it's hard.
如果你离开  这也很难  都很难
If you leave, it's hard. It's all hard.
只是
It's --
有时这和你想要什么根本没关系
Sometimes it's not even about what you want.
而是它想让你怎么样
It's about what it wants for you.
你所能做的只有
All you can do is...
聆听  看看你能否听到它在说什么
listen and see if you can hear what it's saying.
它在说再见
It's saying goodbye.
好  那就上路吧
But, yeah, hit the road, then.
我不想和你说再见
I don't want to say goodbye to you.
当然  亲爱的  最好不是永别
Well, hell, sweetheart, it better not be forever.
我可指望你回来呢
I fully expect you to come back
再次让我振奋起来
and shake me all up again.
别让我变老
Don't let me get old.
你是11点半约的那位吗
You're my 11:30?
不
No.
看看吧
Have a look around.
拱形天花板
Vaulted ceilings,
天花线  社区环境很好
crown molding, great neighborhood.
上一任租客哪去了
What happened to the previous tenant?
不确定  但这地方已经
Not sure, but this has been on the market
在市场上挂了15天了
something like 15 days now.
你确定停在那儿没事吗
Are you sure it's okay out there?
-嗯  他们会绕路的  -好
- Yeah. I mean, they'll go around. - Okay.
我是你的最后一站  对吧
So, I'm, uh, your last stop, huh?
没错
You are.
我今早去了乔那里
I went by Joe's this morning.
他早就走了
He's totally gone.
我没有
Yeah, I didn't, uh --
房产经纪人说那地方已经空了好几周
the real estate agent told me it'd been empty for weeks.
他没有
He didn't...
抱歉  我以为他会打电话的
I'm sorry, I guess I just thought he would call.
老天  乔
God, Joe.
对  他过来说他要走了
Yeah, he, uh, came by here and said he was leaving
他会保持联系的
and that he'd be in touch.
海莉前几天收到了他的信
Haley got a letter from him a couple days ago.
信
A letter?
我猜我俩都喜欢匆匆离开
Well, I guess we're both fond of rash departures.
你可以给我再给我拿一个那种的吗
Could you just bring me one more of those,
-我觉得这样可以了  -唐娜  抱歉
- and I think we'll be fine. - Donna, sorry,
我得说完  我不是...
I'm gonna finish this. I didn't...
故意突然来打断你的
...mean to just burst in on you and the thing you're doing.
不  别这么说  拜托  这不是
No. No, no, no. Please, it's not...
不如你今晚留下来参加吧
why don't you stay for this thing tonight?
-我觉得你也许会喜欢的  -是吗
- I think you might really dig it. - Yeah?
-觉得我不太符合着装要求  -拜托
- Think I'm a little below dress code. - Oh, come on.
你可以借我的穿
You can just borrow something of mine.
不用了  谢谢  感谢你邀请我
No, thank you. I really appreciate it.
我想在傍晚之前
I just -- I wanted to be in Carson City
到卡森城
come nightfall, so...
-我完全明白  -抱歉借过
- Yeah, no, that makes sense, I guess. - Sorry.
天  抱歉
God. Oh. Sorry.
-对不起  -没事的
- I am sorry. - No, no, it's fine.
是硬木地板
It's hardwood.
听着  我
Hey, look, I --
我也希望我们这几个月
I wish we could've hung out more
能多花点时间在一起
these last couple months.
我明白  我也是
Yeah, I know. Me too.
但是工作太忙了  而且
It's just work has been crazy, and...
你知道吗
Well, you know,
也许我走了之后我们会更常见面
probably we'll end up seeing each other more now that I'm gone,
因为我会来城里
'cause I'll come into town,
我们会好好聚聚
and we'll really make a point of it.
你肯定会回来看阿莱克莎  而且
Yeah, and you'll be back seeing Alexa, I'm sure, and...
不
No.
那是过去式了
That's, uh -- That's dead.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
有些事情就是合不来
You know, some things just aren't the right fit.
妈
Mom.
这是我的男朋友凯文
This is my boyfriend, Kevin.
你们好
'Sup?
海莉  卡梅伦要搬走了
Haley, uh, Cameron is moving, I guess.
什么
What?
是的  我要去公路旅行
Yeah, I, uh -- I'm going on a road trip,
等着看会到哪吧
and we'll see, uh, where I -- I end up.
好吧  所有人都要走了
Cool. So everyone's leaving now.
那就  再见
Bye, I guess.
抱歉
Sorry, uh --
-男朋友  -是啊
- Boyfriend? - Yeah.
-门关着你没意见吗  -当然了
- You okay with the door closed? - Oh, yeah, completely.
她只会在里面玩电脑
She just works on her computer,
他就扔沙包玩
and he does the hackey sack.
不出意料
That sounds right.
我觉得她根本就不喜欢他
You know, I get the sense that she doesn't even really like him.
是啊
Yeah.
她在上大学级别的C++课程
She's doing these college-level C++ classes.
在山麓学院  一周上一晚上
It's one night a week at Foothill,
为了这个项目
and she's been just killing herself
她都要把自己弄疯了
over this project,
但她很喜欢
but she loves it.
你能相信吗
Can you believe it?
我相信
I can believe it.
好了  我要走了  顺便把这番茄扔了
Okay, I'm gonna go, uh, and throw this tomato out.
天  抱歉我没接过来
God, I'm sorry I didn't take that.
不是  来  垃圾放在
No, here, the trash is...
-哪里  -我
- Where? - Hey, I'm...
一路平安
Drive safe, okay?
我会想你的
I'm, uh -- I'm gonna miss you.
唐娜  这
Donna, this is --
海莉
Haley?
怎么了
What happened?
我打不开工作文件
I can't open the work file.
我一直在试着打开
I keep trying to open it,
但它提示"驱动器未就绪"
and it says "drive not ready."
你是用沙包砸了电脑吗
Did you hit it with your sack?
-什么  -沙包  凯文
- What? - Hackey, Kev.
没有啊  我就在这儿玩了
No, I've just been chilling here.
这可是我的学期项目
That's my semester project!
-好了  -等等
- Okay. - Hang on.
好了  再试一次
All right, try it again.
是相同的错误提示
It's the same error message.
磁盘没在转
Yeah, the platter's not spinning.
我讨厌这些蠢东西
I hate these stupid things!
深呼吸  凯文  你有钱吗
Breathe. Kevin, do you have any money?
我有感恩节给老人送火鸡
I've got 20 bucks from delivering
赚的20美元
Thanksgiving turkeys to old people.
太好了  那你能帮我个忙
Okay, great, could you do me a favor
带她去看个电影什么的吗
and just take her to a movie or something?
-不  我现在就得做这个  -我知道
- No, I have to do this. - I know.
《星际迷航7:斗转星移》上映了
"Star Trek: Generations" is out.
好吧
Okay, fine.
Okay.
少来啦
Stop.
知道了
Oh, yeah.
磁头卡在盘片上了
Yeah, the head's stuck to the platter.
如果能取出盘片来
If I can get it off and parked,
我们就得检查数据
we'll have to check the data.
只要能启动
Well, as long as it boots,
我就能检查数据
I can go through the contents.
很抱歉  我知道你想开车走了
Sorry about this. I know you wanted to get driving.
不不
No. No,
我又不是那么急着到卡森城
It's not like I'm desperate to see Carson City.
这听起来可不妙
That didn't sound pretty.
但是  已经快好了
But, hey, there we go.
天呐  我要去准备一下了
God, I got to go get ready.
你能接着弄吗
Can you keep going with this?
好
Yeah, yeah.
怎么样了
How's it going in here?
-老天  -怎么了
- Jesus. - What?
不  就是你  你
No, you just -- you...
就是你打扮得太美了
you just do that so well.
是啊  办一场高级的
Yeah. One of the benefits
鸡尾酒晚宴的好处之一
of throwing a fancy cocktail thing.
怎么样
So?
文件损坏了
Well, the file's damaged.
我试试看
I'm trying to figure out
能不能找到别的法子恢复数据
if I can get a side way in to recover the data.
希望能救回一部分
Well, I hope we can save some of it.
这个怎么玩  踢吗
So, what, do you just kick it?
对  对着自己踢
Yeah, you just -- just kick it to yourself.
取胜诀窍呢
How do you win?
用膝盖什么的
You just -- just use your knees and stuff.
我不理解
I don't get it.
我真的很气
You know it really pisses me off,
乔就这样离开了
that Joe would just leave like that.
我们是分手了
Things fell apart, yeah,
但他就这样离开
but for him to just up and...
随便吧
Whatever.
没成
It didn't work.
这里什么都没成  所以
Nothing here did, so...
很抱歉我没告诉你
And I'm sorry that I didn't tell you
我也快要走了
I was leaving sooner.
我就是
I just --
我就是想做个决定
I just wanted to make a decision
不被人劝的回心转意
and not have somebody talk me out of it.
如果你想这么做
Hey, if it's what you want to do,
那就去做吧
it's what you want to do.
是啊
Yeah, man.
如果你一如既往
If you do what you always did,
也也只能得到一贯的结果
you're gonna get what you always got.
如果电梯坏了  就走楼梯
If the elevator's broken, take the stairs.
只要你尝试就会有结果
It works if you work it.
除非有越来越多的解决不了的麻烦
Unless it's more and more of what doesn't work.
匿名见面会上学的
Meetings?
去了几次吧
A few.
你呢
You?
我妈
My mom.
我可能会顺道去看她
I might see her on this trip.
挺好的
That's good.
天  完蛋了
Man, this might be toast.
你把文件转换成
You did copy the file
RTF格式前先复制过了吧
before you converted it to rich text, right?
是的  但我没有转换成RTF格式
Yeah, but I skipped RTF
直接用十六进制编辑器打开了
and went straight to the hex editor.
磁盘头块也重建了  检查下权限
Rebuild the header, too, and check the permissions.
有版本控制也这样做吗
Even if there's version control?
你想恢复数据
You want to recover data
还是想再惹一个15岁的小孩哭
or you want to make a 15-year-old cry again?
好吧
Okay.
要是我们再一起工作呢
What if we worked together again?
那...你有什么点子
What do you, um -- Do you have an idea?
没有  点子可以稍后再想
No, the idea can come later.
那不是重点
That's not what's important.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
这话是有点
That, um -- Oh, God, yeah.
-我  -不不不
- That -- I -- - No. No, no, no, no, no.
-不不不  请忘记我说的话  -抱歉
- No, no, no. Please, forget I said it. - I'm sorry.
我不知道自己在想什么
I -- I don't know what I was thinking.
卡梅隆
Cameron.
抱歉
Sorry.
我去看看办酒宴的人
I'm gonna go check on the caterers.
我马上回来
I'll be back.
那好  我继续想办法
Okay, yeah, I'll keep working on this.
想象一下  我们五个人
So, imagine there are five of us
挤在一辆租来的路虎里
crammed into this rented Land Rover,
而金柏莉又开始晨吐了
and Kimberly already has morning sickness.
而爱尔兰的破路
And the Irish roads are built for,
简直只能跑马车
I don't know, horse-drawn carriages.
而约翰
John --
约翰每看见一朵三叶草
John stops and takes a picture
就要停下来拍照
of every shamrock we see.
每次都停
Every shamrock.
而更重要的是
And more importantly,
你过去这三个月以来
what you have done with the firm
在公司做出的成绩
over the past three months...
谢谢
Thank you.
你的认可真的很重大
That really means a lot.
卡梅伦也来了
Cameron's here.
我还以为她现在得在半个美国开外了
I thought she'd be halfway across the country by now.
我也以为是  她是这么计划的
Yeah, me too. That was the plan.
但是她
But she, um...
她刚刚突发奇想  要和我再次合作
She just floated the idea of working with me again
没来由地就说了
just out of nowhere.
她一半心思想着出远门
With one foot out the door
剩下的生活全塞在一辆房车里吗
and the rest of her life packed in a silver tube?
她就是有这本事
Yeah, well, that is her gift.
异想天开
Thinking of impossible things.
怎么样
Any luck?
好吧
Okay.
电影好看吗
How was the movie?
很奇怪
It was weird.
柯克被困在一个
Kirk was stuck in this, like,
冻结的时间带上
frozen time ribbon thing
然后他重复经历
and he was repeatedly living
他一生最快乐的时光  就这么过了几十年
the happiest part of his life for decades.
然后皮卡德来了  就说
And then Picard comes and he's like,
"哥们  快离开时间带来帮我"
"Dude, get out of the ribbon. You got to help me."
然后柯克就说"成"  然后他就出来了
And so Kirk is like, "Sure," And he does,
然后他  马上就死了
and he, like, immediately dies.
皮卡德真是个混蛋
Picard's a jerk.
你男友哪去了
Where's the Kevinator?
他大概在大吃特吃鞑靼鲔鱼
He's probably wolfing down all the tuna tartare
像条傻梭子鱼似的
like a dumb barracuda.
乔给你写信了吗
Did Joe write you a letter?
写了  怎么了
Yeah. Why?
只是写给我的
it was just to me.
好吧  你说得对  抱歉
Yeah, you're right. Sorry.
你爱过他吗
Did you love him?
是啊
Yeah.
我爱过
I did.
那我  给你简单说说吧
I'll just, like -- I'll just summarize.
他大概就是说他需要重新开始
He said he, like, needs to start over,
而且他没有发布那条彗星广告
and that he didn't air the Comet commercial
因为  你懂的
because, you know, um...
他还提到北卡大学
He talked about UNC
把他们的广播节目放上网了
putting their radio station on the Internet.
什么
What?
是个圈内笑话  你不懂
It's an inside joke. You wouldn't get it.
好吧
Yeah.
他说我爸为我感到骄傲
he said that my dad was proud of me
而且如果他有空回来的话
and that if he was ever in town,
就来看我们
he'd come and see us.
他还说别忘了他
And he said not to forget him,
哪怕我统治了全硅谷
even when I'm running all of Silicon Valley.
这也是他开玩笑
He's joking again.
阿蒙克是哪里
Yeah, Armonk, where is that?
是他的家乡
it's where he's from.
是IBM的所在地
It's where, uh, IBM is.
我很抱歉没能恢复你的数据
Hey, I'm sorry that we couldn't recover your data.
没事
It's fine.
就像乔说的
Like what Joe said.
说什么了
What's that?
重新开始
Fresh start.
也对
Okay.
好吧
Well...
来时间带找我吧
Come find me in the time ribbon.
我会的
I will.
是啊  挺好的
Yes, good.
抱歉失陪一下
If you'll excuse me one second.
谢谢大家
thank you.
我只是...
I just, uh --
我想谢谢你们大家今晚能来
I wanted to thank you guys for coming out tonight.
你们大家[一般指男性]
"You guys."
看看我们的境地
See what we're up against?
我1975年从伯克利毕业
When I graduated from Berkeley in '75
获得了计算机科学的学位
with a degree in computer science,
没人觉得这有什么大不了的
Nobody batted an eye.
那可能是因为那时候
That's probably because back then,
程序员就像秘书和工程师
coders were like secretaries and engineers,
就像是装配流水线上的小兵卒
meaning little solder soldiers on the assembly lines,
基本不受重视
were kind of invisible.
我们都习惯了
And we're used to that.
但不知何时  这些工作变得非常关键
But somewhere along the line, these jobs became important.
别误会
And don't get me wrong,
我随时乐意和"你们大家"一起聚聚
I'm happy to hang out with "you guys" any time
品尝美食
and eat good food,
但我希望等我女儿到我这个年纪
but I hope that by the time my daughters are my age
她们不用像我们这样聚会
that they don't have to have gatherings like this anymore
才能找到自己的存在感
to remind themselves that they're actually here.
我在技术行业做了18年
I've been in tech for 18 years.
有过成功
I've won.
有过失败
And I've lost.
作为女人
I am a woman
我曾经投票将我的女性合伙人踢出公司
who voted her female partner out of her own company,
那是她所创办的公司
the company she founded.
作为女人  为了这份事业
I am a woman who lost a marriage
我失去了很多
to, among other things,
包括我的婚姻
this line of work.
有时候我夜不能寐
I can't sleep at night sometimes
担心我和我孩子见面的时间不够多
worrying if I'm seeing my kids enough
或者我为她们做的不够多
or if I've been there enough for them
或者现在已经太迟了
or if it's already too late.
但是...
But...
我做到了一些事
...I've done things.
那总是需要付出代价  但我还是做到了
That always comes with a price, but I did them.
我学到的很多东西之一
One of the many things I've learned
就是不管你做了什么
is that no matter what you do,
总有人在下个路口
somebody is around the next corner
拿着更好的版本
with a better version of it,
如果那是个男人
and if that person is a man,
那就不仅仅是更好
it might not even be better.
还会得到更多关注
It just might get more attention.
有时候  那个人就是你自己
And sometimes, that person is you.
是永远不满足于自己成果的你
The you that's never satisfied with what you just did
因为你很想继续往下探索
because you're obsessed with whatever is next.
这是唯一不变的
The one constant is this.
是你  是我们
It's you, it's us.
项目将我们与人联接
The project gets us to the people.
因为正是因为这些人  才有了现在的我
Because it's people that got me where I am,
比如黛安·古德
people like Diane Gould.
比如我丈夫
People like my husband
兼第一任合伙人  戈登·克拉克
and my first partner, Gordon Clark.
比如我最后一任也是最棒的合伙人
People like my last and best partner,
卡梅伦·豪伊
Cameron Howe.
对于其他所有人
And for all the rest of you,
我希望今晚能是一个开始
I hope that tonight can be the beginning of something,
今后就算我们
something so that even if we see each other
站在企业竞争的对立面
across the corporate battle lines one day,
你们也知道我支持你们
that you will know that I am rooting for you.
我必须支持
I can't help but not.
因为我的工作是合伙人
Because I am a partner by trade
但我天生是一名母亲和姐妹
and a mother and a sister by design.
我...
And I am --
我很自豪能与你们一起走这段路
I am so proud to be on this journey with you.
天啊
Oh, my God!
不  挺好的
No, this is good.
现在大家都知道你是疯姑娘了
Now everyone knows you were the crazy one.
太好了
Oh, good.
很高兴我能派上点用场
Well, I'm glad I could be of some service.
那...
So...
关于我们一起合作
About working together.
对不起
I'm sorry.
那是个糟糕的主意
It was a terrible idea.
我不该提起来的
I shouldn't have brought it up.
你提出这个提议对我来说
I can't tell you what it means to me
意义非常重大
that you asked.
我觉得我在某种意义上...
I think in some ways, I...
可能等这句话等了很多年了
probably have been waiting for years to hear that.
我是认真的
I meant it.
我知道
I know.
当然了  这是最绝对能
Of course, it is also the surest way
搞砸我们现状的办法
to screw up what we do have now.
我们现在是什么
What do we have now?
我们是朋友
We're friends.
也许我们该看看做朋友怎么样
Maybe we should try that for a while.
你掉进池子里
You falling in that pool
大概是我这辈子
was probably the funniest thing
见过的最搞笑的事了
I've ever seen in my entire life.
凯文去哪了
Hey, where's Kevin?
我把他甩了
I dumped him.
那真是  我很遗憾  你还好吗
Oh, that's -- I'm sor-- Are you okay?
挺好的
Yeah.
话说有时候我总是觉得
You know, sometimes I think maybe --
海莉是同性恋
Haley's gay?
-是啊  -是吧
- Yep. - Yeah.
这俩孩子真是  太了不起了
Oh, these girls, they're just...amazing.
话说原来的穆特尼大楼怎么样了
Hey, what's happening with the old Mutiny building?
我真不敢相信
I mean, I can't believe
他们花了这么多钱装修
they spent all this money redecorating
却没换锁
and didn't even change the stupid lock.
-还铺地毯了  -是啊
- Whoa, carpet. - Yeah.
看看这一排排玻璃
And look at all this glass.
是啊  这就是彗星
Yeah, this was Comet.
好吧  戈登用了你的办公室
Uh, okay, so Gordon was in your office.
当然了
Oh, of course.
而乔占了我的办公室
And Joe was in mine.
戈登改造了以太网
Gordon rewired the ethernet
从天花板上吊下来
so it patched down through the ceiling,
非常天才
which was really genius.
什么
What?
你记不记得莱夫和悠悠球
You remember when, uh, Lev and Yo-Yo
把装满了海猴子的浴缸
took the fish tank full of sea monkeys
-搬到冰箱旁边了  -记得
- and they moved it over by the fridge? - Oh, yeah,
卡尔从上面伸手
and Carl reached over it
过去想拿切达奶酪
trying to get to the Better Cheddars
结果把鱼缸翻在自己身上了
and he spilled it all over himself.
是啊  整条裤子都湿了
Yeah, and he ruined his pants.
-湿得透透的  -所以他不得脱了裤子
- He ruined his pants. - So he had to strip them off,
结果里面穿着  穿着什么来着
and he was wearing-- what was that?
-他穿着那个什么  -就像丁字裤那种
- He was wearing that thing. - It was like a jock strap.
不是不是  是一条比基尼短裤
No, no, no, it was bikini briefs.
天啊  简直像剃光了肉的排骨
Oh, my God. It was like a French cut.
当时他是不是就坐在这儿
Didn't he sit, like, right here?
不是  卡尔在这边  神童旁边
No, Carl, he was over here by Wonderboy.
话说安娜贝尔后来哪去了
Hey, whatever happened to Annabelle?
那个人偶吗
The mannequin?
是啊
Yeah.
博迪在月食之夜
Bodie took mushrooms
服了迷幻药
and immolated her on the roof
在屋顶上把她给献祭了
during a lunar eclipse.
这些人啊
Those guys.
你知道博迪都有四个孩子了吗
You know Bodie has four kids now, right?
扯吧你
Get out.
真的
Yes.
而且神童去纽约大学教书去了
And, uh, oh, Wonderboy teaches at NYU,
不过他教的是视频艺术
but he teaches, like, video art.
挺好的
Oh, cool.
那卡尔呢
What about Carl?
黄片
Porn.
当然了  他留胡子
Oh, of course, 'cause the mustache.
不是  他
No, he --
他在一个网站做主播  还收费的
he hosts it on a website and he charges.
他在阿卡迪亚还是哪来着有一栋大房子
He has a huge house out in Arcadia or somewhere.
会是什么样子呢
What would it be?
如果我们重新再来一次的话
If we were to do it all over again?
我已经想不出点子了
I'm out of ideas.
那我们要怎么经营
Okay, then, how would we run it?
这个嘛
Well...
我们会起名叫
we'd call it, um --
比如说
I don't know.
不死鸟
Phoenix.
我喜欢
Oh, I like it.
股权平分
Equal equity.
联合创始
Co-founders.
有平等的决策权
Equal say in everything.
而这一次我们要按自己的节奏扩张
And we'd just grow at our own pace this time.
认真享受这段历程
Like, really enjoy the ride.
如果我们做两年的纯研发呢
What if we did 24 months of pure R&D?
完全专注于各种超前的创想
Just focus on ideas way outside the box.
还记得我们在不死鸟的第一周吗
You remember our first week at Phoenix?
就你  我  还有那一个我们从
Just you, me, and that one guy we hired
加州理工雇来的人
out of Cal Poly.
我记得我们的首轮融资
I remember our Series A.
然后我们上市了
And then we went public.
嗯
Right.
我们得开始做艰难决定
We had to start making some hard decisions,
或许跟更大的公司合伙
maybe a partnership with a bigger company,
只能牺牲一些公司文化
and we had to sacrifice some of the culture.
嗯  但还是成功了一阵
Yeah, but it worked for a while.
但最终  我们只能解雇了一些人
But eventually we had to let some people go,
梳理组织结构
streamline some things.
但还是继续失地
And still we kept losing ground.
我们开始争论公司的走向
We started arguing about the direction of the company.
我制定了维持现状的安全计划
I strategized a safe play to keep things afloat.
而我则固执己见
And I dug my heels in.
我们争执不下
We fought about it.
但这次我们没有因此分裂
But it didn't destroy us this time.
是啊
No.
但我们还是陷入了僵局
But still, we were at an impasse.
不久后
And then soon enough,
就由不得我们决定了
the decision got made for us.
我们以朋友的身份道别了
And we walked away friends.
能跟你在不死鸟合作真是个荣幸
It was a pleasure working with you at Phoenix.
我享受其中的每一刻
I loved every minute of it.
8, 7, 6, 5,
4, 3, 2, 1.
怎么样了
Now, how we doing?
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
有什么奇怪的感觉吗
Does anything feel weird?
因为就是这样
'Cause that's what this is.
感觉奇怪
Feeling weird is --
才让你知道你还在
is how you know you're still here.
好了  你上次吃饭是什么时候了
All right, now, when was the last time you ate
因为人类只需要食物  水和休息
Because all a human needs is food, water, and rest.
你得提醒自己
You got to remind yourself
你只是72公斤的黏液
that you're just 160 pounds of goo
身处一个巨大的宇宙里
in the middle of a very big universe.
不管你现在为什么不舒服
So whatever's burning you up right now,
要知道那都会过去
just know that it'll fade.
每个问题  当时都感觉很大
Every problem feels big in the moment,
但是  戈登  你该懂的
but, Gordon, you know better.
所以
So...
专注于存在本身
focus on just being being.
偶尔把目光从电脑屏幕上挪开
And then try to look up from your computer every once in a while.
我想尽量去看你
I want to try and see you as much as I can,
但我接下来几周会穿过塔拉哈西
but I should be through Tallahassee in the next couple weeks, so...
我想过去一趟
you know, I thought I could, uh, come by.
嗯
Yeah.
好吧  到时见
Okay, well, then I'll see you then.
我会的  妈妈
Yeah, I will, Mom.
好
Okay.
-打通了吗  -嗯
- Did you get her? - Yeah.
-好  -嗯
- Good. - Yeah.
这周你挺忙吗
So, it's a busy week for you?
是啊
Oh, yeah, sort of.
有家3D成象公司要在计算机分销商展览上亮相
We got a 3-D imaging company presenting at COMDEX,
你懂的  计算机分销商展览嘛
so, you know, it's just COMDEX.
嗯
Yeah.
计算机分销商展览
Oh, COMDEX.
好了  那出发吧
Okay, well, let's do it.
你24小时前就该出发的
What you tried to do 24 hours ago.
我很高兴我耽搁了
I'm glad I got waylaid.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
我来请早餐吧
Hey, I'll get breakfast.
不不  拿来
Oh, no, no. Give me that.
不不  我们分摊吧
No, no, no. Let's split it.
你没工作  省省钱吧
You're unemployed. Save your money.
好吧
Fair enough.
外面见
Meet you outside.
谢谢
Thank you.
卡梅伦
Cameron.
怎么了
What is it?
我有点子了
I have an idea.
我先问个问题
Let me start by asking a question.